signal.co 2017-02-16

# Privacy Policy - Signal

  * Signal Platform Privacy Policy
  * Signal Website Privacy Policy

This policy was last modified on and has an effective date of April 13, 2016

Signal Digital, Inc.( **”Signal”** ) provides this policy to share with you how we treat information that we collect and receive in connection with providing the Signal services to customers who license or otherwise use our technology and services (“ **clients** ”).  Signal provides various services to its clients as described in more detail below, some of which assist our clients with their interest-based advertising campaigns. For information on the opt-out offered by Signal related to interest-based advertising services, [click here](http://privacy.signal.co/opt-out.html).

Each of our clients is responsible for establishing and complying with its own policy and for providing any required notice, obtaining any required consent, and offering and processing any applicable opt-out or similar choice option that the client offers.

This policy does not apply to our clients or any third party organizations. Please refer to the privacy policies for the websites, mobile applications and other online services that you access to learn how they collect and use information about you.

For information about how we handle Personal Information we collect and other information we collect through our websites, please see our [Website Privacy Policy](http://www.signal.co/privacy-policy/#websiteprivacy).

**Table of Contents**

  * Our Services
  * Data Signal Collects or Receives and Stores in Connection with the Services
  * Technologies Used to Collect Usage Data.
    * Cookies and Local Storage
    * Web Beacons
    * Embedded Scripts
    * SDKs and APIs
  * The Purposes for which We Collect, Hold and Use Information
  * Disclosure of Information to Third Parties
  * Your Privacy Choices
    * Mobile Device Opt-Out
    * How We Respond to Do Not Track Signals
  * Security
  * Changes to this Policy

## Our Services

Signal is a service provider. We license proprietary technology and provide data solutions to our clients (the technology and services together, the “ **Services** ”).

Our services include:

  * Integration of tracking tags and other code into client websites, mobile applications and other devices that allows clients and their various third-party marketing and technology partners to collect data relating to user interactions and interests;
  * Collection and distribution of data for the purposes of measuring the effectiveness of websites, mobile applications, advertising campaigns and interactions with other marketing channels;
  * Management and storage of de-identified data that allows our clients to recognize their customers across devices and platforms, to better understand their customers and to engage their customers with more targeted marketing messages.

## Data Signal Collects or Receives and Stores in Connection with the Services

Signal does not have any relationship, contractual or otherwise, with visitors to its clients’ Data Sources. In order to provide the Services to our clients, we collect data from our clients’ websites, mobile applications, advertising impressions, email campaigns, retail stores and other sources (collectively “ **Data Sources** ”).

The information we collect or that clients provide us about their customers we call “ **Client Data** “. “ **Personal Information** ” means information that identifies the user of a Data Source as a specific individual, such as the user’s name, mailing address, email address, or phone number or other information that identifies you as an actual person.

Client Data collected or provided in connection with certain Services (such as analytics), may include Personal Information but we do not use Personal Information in connection with any Services that assist clients with their interest-based advertising. Note that in providing the Services, we do not collect any Personal Information on our own behalf – we collect information on behalf of our clients as service provider to those clients. We only store, use and share Personal Information collected through our Services as directed by our clients on their behalf.

We do not use Personal Information in connection with advertising-related Services. For advertising related Services, we do use and store data that has been de-identified, which is typically accomplished using a mathematical process (commonly known as a hash function) to convert information into a code that we cannot use to identify you directly. We combine this information with other de-identified information collected from or provided by other client Data Sources in order to help our clients recognize their customers and infer customer interests and preferences.

In order to provide the Services to our clients, we automatically collect certain information about your use of our client’s Data Sources when you visit or interact with those Data Sources (“ **Usage Data** ”). We collect a variety of Usage Data including, for example:

  * IP address and other unique identifier for any computer, mobile phone, or other device used to access the client’s Data Sources (“ **device identifier** ”);
  * Information about a visitor’s Web browser and device;
  * Information about visitor interactions with the client’s Data Source, such as content viewed and products purchased;
  * Information regarding a user’s preferences and interests;
  * Demographic data, such as age and gender; and
  * Location information.

We consider the following “Sensitive Data,” and we do not use this Sensitive Data in connection with interest-based advertising Services:

  * racial or ethnic origin;
  * sexual preferences or practices;
  * criminal record;
  * health information;
  * genetic information that is not otherwise health information; or
  * biometric information or templates.

We further limit the collection and use of sensitive data as defined and required by applicable law in certain jurisdictions. For example, some jurisdictions define sensitive data to further include:

  * political opinions;
  * membership of a political association;
  * religious beliefs or affiliations;
  * philosophical beliefs;
  * membership of a professional or trade association;
  * membership of a trade union.

We may also supplement Client Data with outside records from third parties, and we treat the combined data as described in this Services Privacy Policy.

## Technologies Used to Collect Usage Data.

We use many technologies to collect Usage Data. Some examples include:

**Cookies and Local Storage.** Cookies and local storage are data files placed within a browser on a device when it is used to visit a Data Source. Cookies and local storage can both be used to store a unique identifier for your device that can be used to recognize your device whenever you visit a client Data Source. Most browsers provide you with the ability to disable or decline cookies and local storage. You will need to check your browser’s settings for further information.

**Web Beacons.** Web Beacons are small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1×1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) that are included in our clients’ Data Sources.

**Embedded Scripts**. An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with a Data Source. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our web server, is active only while you are connected to the Data Source, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

**SDKs and APIs**. SDKS and APIs are programming codes that collect information about your interactions with a Data Source. This code is installed on a Device, typically within our clients’ applications that you choose to download onto your mobile device.

These technologies, and similar technologies we may use, and the information they collect may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, tracking your visits to Data Sources, monitoring how you navigate a Data Source and determining your preferences and interests for the purposes of serving you targeted advertisements and other marketing messages.

Signal may receive Client Data through certain technology or services that clients license through affiliated services, including those offered by Signal Digital, Inc., if the client utilizes the services of both companies. We use all information we collect and receive in accordance with this policy.

## The Purposes for which We Collect, Hold, and Use Information

We collect, hold and use de-identified information from clients to provide the Services, including to infer your interests and preferences and to allow our clients and others to target advertisements and offers to you based on those interests and preferences. Apart from the above instances, we may also collect, hold, and use information collected or received in connection with the Services to provide the Services, to improve the Services, for our internal business purposes and to meet any legal requirements or needs. Click [opt out tool](http://privacy.signal.co/opt-out.html) for information on how you may opt-out of having information we collect or infer about you or your device for targeted advertising purposes.

## Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

  * **Non-identifying data.** We may share non-identifying data, including aggregate statistics and hashed or otherwise de-identified data, with third parties.

  * **Client Data.** We may transfer Client Data and inferences about that Client Data to the client or to a third party (including, without limitation, advertising networks) at the client’s direction. We may share inferred interests and preferences and other Client Data with multiple clients and advertising networks and this information may be connected to your IP address, device identifier, or other information that our client has collected from you (including hashed Personal Information).

  * **Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf or on Behalf of Our Clients**. Third parties who provide services to us may have access to information, including Personal Information, in order to perform services for us or on behalf of our clients.

  * **Administrative and Legal Reasons**. We may transfer and disclose information, including Client Data, to third parties: (i) to respond to subpoenas or other legal processes or if in our opinion the disclosure is required by law; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; or (iii) to respond to an emergency or otherwise to protect the safety, rights, property or security of any person or entity.

  * **Business Transfers**. We may disclose and transfer Client Data: (a) if we assign our rights regarding any of the information to a third party or (b) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, sale of certain of Signal and/or its parent company ownership interests, assets, or both, bankruptcy or other corporate change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

  * **For other purposes**. We may transfer and disclose Client Data to other third parties as otherwise required by law.

## Your Privacy Choices

We understand that you may wish to opt-out of our use of information about you or your devices to provide targeted advertising services to our clients. Please note that the opt-out choices below apply only with regard to our use of information associated with your devices for interest-based advertising purposes. Please note that it may take up to 7 days to process your opt-out request.

Signal is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and adheres to the NAI code of conduct. You may use the NAI [opt out tool](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), which will allow you to opt out of seeing targeted ads through your web browser from NAI member companies. We also support the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising as managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA). You can visit the DAA opt-out page here: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

In addition, to opt-out of Signal’s use of information through your Web browser for targeted advertising purposes, please click [here](http://privacy.signal.co/opt-out.html). Please note that we use cookies to implement your opt-out choice. If you delete our opt-out cookie(s), we will not be able to ensure that your information is no longer used to provide our Services, unless you return to this page and opt-out again. If your browser is not configured to accept third-party cookies, then your opt-out preference cannot be stored.

For mobile apps, you can typically limit ad tracking using the settings on your phone, tablet or other mobile device using the “Ads” menu, “Ad Tracking” setting, or similar setting on your device.

Please be aware that opting out does not mean that you will no longer receive targeted marketing messages in your mobile apps or Web browsers. You may still receive generic advertisements and you may see targeted advertisements based on information collected and used by entities other than Audience Trust.

## How We Respond To Do Not Track Signals

Your web browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to websites and online services you visit.  Like many websites and online services, Signal does not alter its practices when it receives a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit http://www.allaboutdnt.com.

## Data Retention

We retain client data as long as it is active, which we consider to be up to one year from the date of the last update made by the client.  Therefore, if a client uploads a customer record and makes no changes to that record, then it will automatically be deleted from our system after one year. Every time a client updates the customer record, then the one year counter begins again.  We also retain data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Security

We take commercially reasonable steps to help protect and secure Client Data (including against unauthorized access, modification and disclosure, and from other types of misuse, interference and loss). However, no data transmission over the Internet or wireless connection, or electronic storage of data, can be guaranteed to be completely secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information we collect or store.

## Changes to this Policy

We may change this policy from time to time, and any changes will be effective as soon as we post the revised policy on this Website, unless a different date is stated. You should review this policy regularly.

## Any Questions?

If you have questions or comments about this Policy, you can contact us at: privacy@signal.co

* * *

This policy was posted and has an effective date of **July 27, 2015.**

Signal Digital, Inc. ( “Signal”) provides this Website Privacy Policy to share with you how we treat personal information about you that we collect and receive in connection with your use of our websites, features, and applications that post a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, our “Websites”). Please note that certain features or services referenced in this Privacy Policy may not be offered on each of our Websites at all times.

_This Privacy Policy only applies to our Websites._ Signal also works with clients who license and use our technology and services. If you are a consumer and would like to understand our privacy practices in connection with the Signal services used by our clients, please review [Signal’s Platform Privacy Policy](http://www.signal.co/privacy-policy/)

## Information We Collect

In general, you can visit our Websites without providing us with any “Personal Information” (information that identifies you as a specific individual, such as your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, or other information that identifies you as an actual person). However, you may choose to submit Personal Information through our Websites, and we may request other information about you, such as demographic information (e.g., your age, gender, ZIP code or similar information), information about your employer, and your preferences or interests. We will also collect payment information if you choose to purchase products or services through the Websites. If we combine these types of other information about you with Personal Information, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Website Privacy Policy.

You should know that we also may receive information (including Personal Information) about you from third parties. For example, if you are on another website and you opt-in to receive information from Signal, that website will provide your contact and other information to us so that we may contact you as requested. Third parties may also provide information about you in connection with our Social Features. We may also supplement the information we collect with outside records from third parties. If we combine the information we receive from others with information we collect through our Websites, we will treat the combined information as described in this Website Privacy Policy.

If you provide us with personal information about a third party, you represent, and we collect it on the basis that, you have that person’s consent for us to collect and handle their personal information in accordance with this Website Privacy Policy.

We also automatically collect Usage Information as you visit and interact with our Websites, as further described below.

Generally, except as necessary for any application for employment (see below WHEN YOU APPLY FOR A JOB THROUGH OUR WEBSITES), or otherwise with your consent, we do not collect certain types of Personal Information (known as Sensitive Information) about you such as:

  * racial or ethnic origin;
  * political opinions;
  * membership of a political association;
  * religious beliefs or affiliations;
  * philosophical beliefs;
  * membership of a professional or trade association;
  * membership of a trade union;
  * sexual preferences or practices;
  * criminal record;
  * health information;
  * genetic information that is not otherwise health information; or
  * biometric information or templates.

We will assume that you have consented to us collecting all information, which is provided to us by you for use in accordance with this Website Privacy Policy, including any ‘Sensitive Information’, unless you tell us otherwise. Sensitive information will be used in accordance with the applicable law of your jurisdiction.

Our Websites are not intended for use by anyone younger than the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children younger than age 13. If we learn that we have in fact collected Personal Information from a user younger than 13, we will delete it from our active databases.

## Blog Posts, Public Comments & Social Features

The Websites may provide you the opportunity to participate and post content publicly through interactive features and through other communication functionality such as on the Signal Blog (“ **Public Comments** “). Please note that certain information, such as your name, may be publicly displayed on the Websites along with your Public Comments, and that others will have access to your Public Comments and may use them or share them with third parties. If you choose to voluntarily disclose Personal Information in connection with your Public Comments, that information will be considered public information and the protections of this Privacy Policy will not apply. To request removal of your Personal Information from Public Comments, contact us at privacy@signal.co. Given the nature of the Internet it is not possible to completely remove content as though it never appeared. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Some websites and third party services also permit interactions between the Website and a third-party social network or other third-party website or service, such as sharing content or distributing a message on or through a social network, or enabling you to “like” or “share” Website content on a third-party service (“ **Social Features** ”). If you choose to share content or to otherwise post information through the Websites to a third-party site or service, or vice versa, that information may be publicly displayed. Both Signal and the third-party may have access to certain information about you and your use of the Websites and the third-party site or service. In addition, Signal may receive information about you if other users of a third-party web site give us access to their profiles and you are one of their “connections” or information about you is otherwise accessible through your “connections” web page, profile page, or similar page on a social networking or other third-party web site or interactive service. The information Signal collects in connection with Social Features is subject to this Privacy Policy. The information collected and stored by the third party remains subject to the third party’s privacy practices, including whether the third party continues to share information with us, the types of information shared, and your choices with regard to what is visible to others on that third-party website or service.

## Information About Your Visit To Our Websites

As described below, we and our third-party service providers may use certain technologies (such as cookies and Web beacons) that automatically or passively collect certain information whenever you interact with our Websites (“Usage Information”). Usage Information may include the browser and operating system you are using, the URL or advertisement that referred you to our Websites, any search terms you entered into a search engine that led you to our Websites, the areas within our Websites that you visited, and the time of day you visited our Websites, among other information. Usage Information also includes the IP address or other unique identifier (“Device Identifier”) for any computer, mobile phone, or other device used to access our Websites. A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your device, and our servers identify your device by its Device Identifier. Some mobile service providers may also provide us with information regarding the physical location of the device you used to access our Websites. Usage Information is generally non-identifying, but if we associate it with you as a specific and identifiable person, we will treat it as Personal Information.

## Use Of Cookies, Web Beacons And Similar Tracking Technologies

We and our third-party service providers, including third-party advertisers and analytics providers, may use the following or similar technologies to collect Usage Information whenever you visit our Websites:

## Cookies And Local Storage

A “cookie” is a data file stored on your computer’s hard disk or similar device when you retrieve content from a Web server. Cookies may be stored on your device for different periods of time depending on how they are used. “Session cookies” store information that is only relevant for your current activity and are no longer accessible after you shut down your browser. “Persistent cookies” remain after you close your browser and may be accessed by your browser on subsequent visits. When you visit our Websites, both session and persistent cookies may be transferred to your device.

Certain Web browsers and certain browser add-ons such as Adobe Flash may provide additional local data storage mechanisms that are used in a manner similar to cookies, and some of the content included on our Websites may make use of this local storage. For example, a Flash cookie is a data file placed on a device via the Adobe Flash plugin that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your device. For more information about Adobe Flash and the privacy choices this technology offers, visit http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html.

Cookies, local storage and Flash cookies may be used for a variety of purposes, e.g., to identify your device when you revisit our Websites, to recall your authentication information, or to store information related to your navigation throughout our Websites, or to enable certain features on our Websites.

Your browser may allow you to refuse or remove some or all of these cookie and local storage technologies. For specific instructions, please consult the manufacturer of your Web browser software.

## Web Beacons

We may also employ software technology known as “web beacons” or “tracking tags” to help us keep track of what content on our Websites is effective and to serve relevant advertising to you. Web beacons are small graphics with a unique identifier that may be invisible to you, and which are used to track the online activity of Internet users. Web beacons are embedded in the web pages you review or email messages you receive. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to our Websites, to monitor how users navigate the Websites, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened, or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

In addition, we may use a variety of other technologies that collect similar information for security and fraud detection purposes.

## How We Respond To “Do Not Track” Signals

Note that your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to websites and online services you visit. Like many websites and online services, Signal currently does not alter its practices when it receives a “Do Not Track” Signal from a visitor’s browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit www.allaboutdnt.com.

## Purposes For Which Information Is Collected, Held, And Used

We will collect, hold, and use information about you (including Personal Information and Usage Information) for the purposes for which we collected it, and for other related purposes that you would reasonably expect. Generally, these purposes include using information collected through our Websites, including your Personal Information and Usage Information, to (a) enable you to use our Websites, and to provide related user service, including responding to your questions, complaints, or comments; (b) fulfill transactions and process orders and payments; (c) administer and develop our business relationship with you and the company you represent; (d) provide you with information, products or services that you have requested or agreed to receive or that we otherwise believe will interest you, including sending you information and special offers from us, including our affiliated or parent companies, and on behalf of our third party business partners; (e) tailor content, recommendations and offers we display to you, both on the Websites and elsewhere online, (f) conduct internal analyses, such as surveys and market research, to improve our Websites, our products and services, and for other internal business purposes; (g) process information you provide via our Websites, including verifying that your e-mail address is active and valid; (h) contact you with administrative communications and, in our discretion, changes to this Website Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, or any of our other policies, (i) assess your employment application for a position with Signal or an entity related to Signal and prepare related governmental and internal statistics reports, and (j) for purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent, and as further described in this Website Privacy Policy.

## Analytics Providers, Ad Servers, and Similar Third Parties

Although our Websites currently do not display ads from third parties, we work with network advertisers, ad agencies, analytics service providers and other vendors to provide us with information regarding traffic on our Websites, including pages viewed and the actions taken when visiting our Websites; to serve our advertisements on other websites, within mobile apps and elsewhere online, and to provide us with information regarding the use of our Websites and the effectiveness of our advertisements. For example, if you view or click on an advertisement for Signal or one of our products, our service provider(s) may be able to tell us the advertisement that you clicked on and where you were viewing the advertisement. The advertisements you see may be served by one or more third parties, who may use information about your visits to or activities on our Websites and other websites or services to provide you with targeted advertisements.

Our service providers may set and access their own tracking technologies on your device (including cookies and web beacons) and may otherwise collect or have access to information about you and your visits to and activity on the Websites, as well as on other websites or online services. Some of these third parties may collect personal information from you over time when you visit the Websites or other websites and services. Cookies and web beacons, including those set by third party network advertisers, may be used to, among other things, target advertisements, prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times and conduct research regarding the usefulness of certain advertisements to you. We may share Usage Information about visitors with third party advertising companies, analytics providers and other vendors for similar purposes.

We use a variety of service providers to perform advertising services. Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) or the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. You may want to visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and the “opt-out” procedures of NAI members. You may also want to visit or http://www.aboutads.info/choices/, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and offers an “opt-out” by participating companies in the DAA Self-Regulatory Program. Please note opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads while online.

## Testimonials

We display customer testimonials on our Websites. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name, photograph, and other identifying information.

## Sharing Your Information With Third Parties

We may share non-personally identifiable information, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties. We also may share the information we have collected about you, including Personal Information and Usage Information, as disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent, as described in this Website Privacy Policy, and in the following circumstances:

## Third Party Marketing Partners

We may share the Personal Information we collect through the Websites with our subsidiaries and affiliates, and with third party business and marketing partners, and those third parties may reach out to you for their own marketing purposes. We will not share Personal Information with third party business and marketing partners without your consent if consent is required by applicable law in your jurisdiction.

**_California Residents_** : for information on how to request additional information about third parties with whom we share Personal Information for their own marketing purposes, please click here.

## Third Parties Providing Services On Our Behalf

We may provide third parties with access to your Personal Information to provide services to us or to you, such as website hosting, sending emails or other communications, providing marketing assistance and data analysis, processing payment information, providing customer assistance, or collecting and processing information on our behalf. These third party companies are contractually bound by Signal to use Personal Information that we share with them only to perform the services we have hired them to provide.

## Administrative and Legal Reasons

We may transfer and disclose information, including your Personal Information, to third parties: (i) to respond to subpoenas or other legal process or if in our opinion the disclosure is required by law; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; or (iii) to enforce our Terms of Use or other applicable Website policies; (iv) to respond to an emergency or otherwise to protect the safety, rights, property, or security of Signal or others. We may also use Device Identifiers to identify users and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, online or wireless service providers, or law enforcement agencies in our discretion.

## Business Transfers

Signal may share your information, including Personal Information, with its parent, subsidiaries, and affiliates. We may also disclose and transfer your information, including your Personal Information (a) to a future owner, co-owner, or operator of one of our Websites or applicable database or (b) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, sale of certain of Signal’s ownership interests, assets, or both, or other corporate change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

## Your Choices: Marketing Communications and Opting Out

By providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to us using your Personal Information to provide you with promotional and marketing communications as set out above. You agree to receive such communications by post, phone or by electronic means (including e-mail).

You may opt out of receiving promotional and marketing communications from us by emailing us at privacy@signal.co or by using the opt-out mechanism included in the commercial emails we send. If you email us, please title your email “COMMUNICATIONS OPT-OUT REQUEST.” Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your use of our Websites, service announcements, notices of changes to this Website Privacy Policy or our Terms of Use or similar administrative or transactional messages, and you may continue to receive these transactional account messages even if you choose to opt-out from marketing communications. We may provide additional opt-out options for marketing communications in those communications.

## Information Access And Updating Your Information

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as your contact information, either through any online account feature offered or by contacting us. You may access the Personal Information we hold about you by contacting our customer service department by email at privacy@signal.co In addition, at any time you can request that we modify or delete your Personal Information that we hold about you if you believe it is inaccurate, incomplete, out-of-date, irrelevant or misleading by sending an email to us at privacy@signal.co with the words “UPDATE MY INFORMATION” in the subject line. Please be aware that, to protect your security and privacy, we may take reasonable steps to verify your identity prior to making changes to your Personal Information.  Generally, we will provide you with access, except in limited circumstances where the law permits us to deny access. No fee will be incurred for requesting access, but if your request for access is accepted we will inform you of the fee (if any) that will be payable for providing access if you proceed with your request.

We will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our active databases as soon as reasonably practicable (unless we are required by law not to do so. Note, however, that information you update or change may persist internally or for our administrative purposes. It is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases, and residual data may remain on backup media or for other reasons.

## Links To Other Sites And Interactions With Third-Party Services

Our Websites may include third-party content or links to third-party sites that we do not control. These third parties’ practices regarding information collection, use, and sharing may be different than ours. We are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by any third party.

## When You Apply For A Job Through Our Websites

If you apply for a job through our Websites, we, or a human resources company helping us out, may ask you to provide self-identifying information (such as veteran status, gender and ethnicity) in conjunction with laws and regulations enforced by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (“EEOC”), the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs (“OFCCP”), and similar state and local regulatory agencies. Providing self-identifying information is voluntary, but if you do provide us with that information, we may submit it to the EEOC, the OFCCP and similar state and local regulatory agencies for business-related purposes, including responding to information requests, fulfilling regulatory reporting requirements and defending against employment related complaints.

## Visitors Residing Outside Of The United States And Consent To Transfer

**_Signal is a United States company._** If you are located in the European Union or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that information you provide to us will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using our Websites, or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States. You should know that privacy laws in the United States may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside or are a citizen.

**_Australian Residents_** : You acknowledge and agree that when we disclose any Personal Information we have collected to a recipient outside of Australia then: (a) that information may go to a country that has different privacy laws than Australia (and which may not be comparable), and (b) it will be handled in accordance with the laws of that country, and not necessarily with Australian privacy law, and (c) that we may not take steps to ensure that the overseas recipient handles your Personal Information in accordance with Australian privacy. You consent to us disclosing your Personal Information to recipients located outside of Australia on that basis.

## Security

We take commercially reasonable steps to help protect and secure the Personal Information that we hold about you (including from unauthorized access, modification and disclosure, and from other types of misuse, interference and loss).

However, no data transmission over the Internet or wireless connection, or electronic storage of data, can be guaranteed to be completely secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information we collect via our Websites or the Internet. You use our Websites and provide us with your information at your own risk.

You should take steps to safeguard your own computer or mobile device and password protect against unauthorized access by others. If you have an account on our Websites, do not disclose your login, password or other account information to any person.

## Complaints

If you have a complaint about the way in which we handle your Personal Information please contact on the details below. We will confirm receipt of your complaint and set out the time frame we require to investigate your complaint and provide you with a response, which generally, will be within 14 days of receiving your complaint.

## Changes To This Website Privacy Policy

We may change this Website Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes we make will be effective as soon as we post the modified policy on our Websites. If you continue to use our Websites after we post the modified policy, then you have accepted the modified policy and any information we collect or you provide after that will be treated as described in the modified policy. If we make material changes to how we use or share your Personal Information, those changes will not apply with respect to Personal Information collected or provided before we posted the revised policy without your consent.

## California Residents: Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents who provide us with personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us one time per calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year.

If you are a California resident, to obtain information free of charge regarding our sharing of personal information with third parties, including affiliated companies or our parent, for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, please write to us at Signal, ATTN: California Privacy Rights, 111 N. Canal St., Suite 455, Chicago, IL 60606 or submit your request via e-mail at privacy@signal.co. You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field of your e-mail or in a prominent position on any mailed request. You must include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We will respond to you at your mailing address, or at our option, your e-mail address. We are not responsible for requests that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each calendar year.

## Any Questions?

If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at: privacy@signal.co.
